ILGWU 75th Anniversary Proclamation from a variety of sources 6036/004
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
ILGWU 75th Anniversary Proclamation from a variety of sources
1975
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union (ILGWU)
6036/004
0.83 cubic feet
0.8 linear ft.
Records.
Collection of proclamations from American city and state governments issued in observance of the ILGWU's 75th anniversary.
5767217
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
R. Miles, August 11, 2009
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, February 17, 2016
Biographical / Historical
The International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union was once one of the largest labor unions in the United States founded in 1900 by local union delegates representing about 2,000 members in cities in the northeastern United States. It was one of the first U.S. Unions to have a membership consisting of mostly females, and it played a key role in the labor history of the 1920s and 1930s. The union is generally referred to as the "ILGWU" or the "ILG". The ILGWU grew in geographical scope, membership size, and political influence to become one of the most powerful forces in American organized labor by mid-century. Representing workers in the women's garment industry, the ILGWU worked to improve working and living conditions of its members through collective bargaining agreements, training programs, health care facilities, cooperative housing, educational opportunities, and other efforts. The ILGWU merged with the Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union in 1995 to form the Union of Needle trades, Industrial and Textile Employees (UNITE). UNITE merged with the Hotel Employees and Restaurant Employees Union (HERE) in 2004 to create a new union known as UNITE HERE. The two unions that formed UNITE in 1995 represented only 250,000 workers between them, down from the ILGWU's peak membership of 450,000 in 1969.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
5767217
- Albany, New York, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Aurora, Illinois, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Bardstown, Kentucky, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Bay City, Michigan, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Bayonne, New Jersey, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Benton, Illinois, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Bridgeport, Connecticut, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Brownsville, Kentucky, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Canton, Ohio, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Carteret, New Jersey, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Chicago, Illinois, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Cincinnati, Ohio, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Cleveland, Ohio, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Cohoes, New York, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Connecticut, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Danbury, New Jersey, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Detroit, Michigan, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- East Orange, New Jersey, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Fairfield, Illinois, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Gary, Indiana, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Glasgow, Kentucky, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Glens Falls, New York, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Green Island, New York, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Hagerstown, Maryland, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Hartford, Connecticut, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Herrin, Illinois, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Highland, Illinois, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Indiana, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Jackson, Michigan, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Kentucky, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 30)
- La Crosse, Wisconsin, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Lackawanna, Pennsylvania, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Lawrenceburg, Kentucky, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 33)
- Little Rock, Arkansas, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 34)
- Logansport, Indiana, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 35)
- Lorain, Ohio, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 36)
- Martins Ferry, Ohio, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 37)
- Meriden, Connecticut, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 38)
- Michigan, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 39)
- Mount Carmel, Illinois, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 40)
- Mount Vernon, New York, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 41)
- New Britain, Connecticut, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 42)
- New Haven, Connecticut, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 43)
- Newark, New Jersey, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 44)
- North Bergen, New Jersey, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 45)
- North Little Rock, Arkansas, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 46)
- Passaic, New Jersey, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 47)
- Pottsville, Pennsylvania, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 48)
- Rockland, New Jersey, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 49)
- Salem, Illinois, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 50)
- Suffolk County, New York, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 51)
- Summit Hill, Pennsylvania, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 52)
- Trenton, New Jersey, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 53)
- Troy, New York, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 54)
- Vermont, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 55)
- West Haven, Connecticut, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 56)
- West Orange, New Jersey, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 57)
- Wooster, Ohio, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 58)
- Harrodsburg, Kentucky, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Jersey City, New Jersey, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Los Angeles, California, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Nassau County, New York, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- New Rochelle, New York, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- New York, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Ohio, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Pennsylvania, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Rhode Island, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Richmond, New York City, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Saint Louis, Missouri, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Saint Louis County, Missouri, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Toledo, Ohio, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Westchester County, New York, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Wisconsin, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Yonkers, New York, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- New York, New York, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 17)